(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ずっと話したかった
I've always wanted to talk to you.
無くしてしまった夜の言葉
About the words of the night that I've lost.
悲しい話じゃない 寂しくなるけど
It's not a sad story, although it makes me lonely.
いいんだ
It's okay.
君の夜をくれ
作詞・作曲：古川本舗
Give Me Your Night
Lyrics & Composition: Furukawa Honpo
灯をずっと消したままで 眠れない日は
On days when I can't sleep with the lights turned off.
冷めてしまったコーヒーに逃げ込んでみる
I try to take refuge in my cold coffee.
借りたままだったレコードに針を落としたら
If I drop the needle on the record I borrowed.
情けないステップで踊り出せる
I can start dancing with pathetic steps.
ずっと ずっと 待ち焦がれた
I've been waiting for so long.
明け方の陽も消えない今日も
For the morning light, even today when it doesn't fade.
今夜 今日のこの夜に
Tonight, in this very night.
沈んでしまっても
Even if it sinks away.
きっと街の影を 照らす明かりが
Surely, the lights illuminating the shadows of the city.
昨日と違って 柔らかく見えたから
Looked softer than yesterday.
目を閉じるよ
I'll close my eyes.
眠りにつくよ
I'll fall asleep.
君の夜をくれ
Give me your night.
ずっと ずっと 聞きたかった
I've always wanted to hear it.
明け方の陽に笑い合う声を
Our voices laughing together in the morning light.
今夜 今日のこの夜も
Tonight, this night as well.
終わってしまうけど
It will come to an end, but...
灯は小さく点けたまま 目を伏せて
Leaving the light on low, I cast my eyes down.
冷めたままの
Swallowing down the coffee
コーヒーを喉に流して
that has gone cold
借りたままだった
If tears spill onto the record
レコードに涙がこぼれたら
I still haven't returned
情けない僕を
Please laugh at my miserable self
また笑ってくれ
once again
きっと街の影を
Surely, the lights
照らす明かりが
illuminating the shadows of the city
昨日と違って
looked softer than they did yesterday
柔らかく見えたから
softer than they did yesterday
暖かさに
Because of that warmth,
今日は眠れるよ
I'll be able to sleep today
君の夜をくれ
Give me your night
I remember you
作詞・作曲：YUI
Lyrics & Composition: YUI
風はもう
The wind is already
冷たいけれど
cold, but
懐かしい空の
there was a nostalgic scent
匂いがしたんだ
in the sky
ホームから
In this place where the sea is visible
海が見える
from the platform
この場所で
In this place,
君を捜してる
I'm searching for you
季節はずれの
On an out-of-season
サーフボードに
surfboard
あの夏はきっと
that summer surely
生きてる
lives on
太陽はずっと
The sun must have
覚えていたはずさ
remembered it all along
ねえ　聞こえてる？
Hey, can you hear me?
涙は見せないって
“I won’t show my tears,”
君はそう言って
you said that
僕たちはふたり
and the two of us
手を振った
waved our hands
さよならは言わないで
“Don't say goodbye,”
だから手を振った
that's why we waved
夕焼けに消えた
Vanished into the sunset,
I remember you
錆びたギター
Every time I hold
抱えるたびに
my rusty guitar
あの歌が胸の
that song grips
奥をつかむけど
the depths of my heart
今もまだ
Even now,
冴えない日々
in these unremarkable days
この場所で
in this place,
僕を過ごしてる
I'm living my life
だけど思うんだ
But I think,
誰かのために
surely we live
きっと僕らは
for the sake of
生きてる
someone else
太陽がきっと
The sun surely
教えてくれたんだ
taught me that
ねえ　聞こえてる？
Hey, can you hear me?
涙は見せないって
“I won’t show my tears,”
君はそう言って
you said that
僕たちはふたり
and the two of us
手を振った
waved our hands
さよならは言わないで
“Don't say goodbye,”
だから手を振った
that's why we waved
夕焼けに消えた
Vanished into the sunset,
I remember you
あれからの僕は
Since then,
相変わらず
I haven't changed
だけど
But
ほんの少し
I have just
自信があるんだ
a little bit of confidence
涙をこらえて
Holding back my tears,
約束だから
because it's a promise
誰よりも強くならなくちゃ
I have to become stronger than anyone else
さよならは言わないで
Don't say goodbye,
だって目を閉じて
because I can see you immediately
すぐに会える
if I close my eyes
I remember you
放送室
作詞・作曲：MI8k
Housoushitsu (Broadcast Room)
Lyrics & Composition: MI8k
考えてたことが言葉に出ない
The things I was thinking about won't come out in words
先走った後悔と汗が手に残る
Remaining in my hands are hasty regrets and sweat
ただ真っ直ぐに見ていたいだけなのに
Even though I just want to look straight ahead
今日も見切りをつけた　部屋真っ暗にしてしまった
Today too, I've given up and made my room pitch black
ああ　部屋を消滅させている
Ah, I'm making the room vanish
この部屋宇宙の端線だ
This room is the borderline of the universe
私から出た SOS だけ届いてないよな
Only the SOS I sent out isn't reaching, right?
涙をずっとしまってる　どんな結末があるかを見たくて
I've been holding back my tears,
wanting to see what kind of ending there will be
完成するまで悲しみを拒んでいる
Rejecting sadness until it's complete
不安を感じていたのが体のどこか知らないけど
I don't know where in my body I was feeling anxiety, but...
こんな場所でまで響き続けていく
It continues to resonate even in a place like this
理由を見つけたんだ
I've found the reason
変えられない呼吸も鼓動も
Neither the unchangeable breathing nor the heartbeat
不安定な形も完璧に見えるとき
Even the unstable shape looks perfect at times
今更後ろ見ない　振り向くのは怖い
I won't look back now, it's scary to turn around
この場所だけは私のこと知ってるんだ
Only this place knows about me
手を引いて向かう場所示すのだ
Taking my hand and showing me where to go
そう思えば強く輝けるから
Because thinking so makes me shine brighter
届いてほしいのは SOS じゃなくて優しい言葉
What I want to reach you is not an SOS,
but kind words
涙をずっとしまっても　笑顔のままでいる姿で
Even if I hold back my tears, with a smile on my face
駆け抜け君のもとまで最短で辿り着くよ
I'll run through and reach you in the shortest distance
孤独を感じていたのが体のどこか知らないけど
I don't know where in my body I was feeling loneliness, but...
ほんの少しでも君に近づきたい
I want to get even just a little closer to you
何かが変わればいい
I hope something changes
私から出た優しい言葉だけ
Only the kind words that came from me
君に届いてほしい
I want them to reach you
小さな宇宙に生まれただけ
Just born into a small universe
遠い場所から君を見つけただけ
Just found you from a distant place
涙をずっとしまってる　どんな結末になるかを知りたくて
I've been holding back my tears,
wanting to know what kind of ending it will be
完成するまでサヨナラは拒んでいる
Rejecting goodbyes until it's complete
不安を感じていたのが体のどこか知らないまま
While still not knowing where in my body I was feeling anxiety
こんな場所でまで響き続けていく
It continues to resonate even in a place like this
理由を見つけたんだ
I've found the reason
皆さん、たくさん盛り上がっていきましょう！
Everyone, let's keep the excitement going!
星座になれたら
作詞：樋口愛 作曲：内藤英徳
Seiza ni naretara (If I Could Be a Constellation)
Lyrics: Ai Higuchi Composition: Hidenori Naito
もうすぐ時計は九時
It'll soon be nine o'clock
もうそこに一番星
And the first star is already there
影を踏んで　夜に紛れたくなった帰り道
I wanted to step on shadows and disappear into the night
on my way home
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search
一つしかない星
There's only one star
何億光年　離れたところからあんなに輝く
Shining so brightly from billions of light-years away
君はいつも みんなから愛されていいな
It's nice how you're always loved by everyone.
僕は ずっと 一人きりさ
I've always been all alone.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
A wish for a moment on a starry night.
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
A sparkling, flickering, trembling signal.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて 指を差されるような
To be pointed at while looking up at the sky.
つないだ線 解かないで
Don't untie the lines we've connected
僕がどんなにまぶしくても
No matter how dazzling I might be.
もうすぐ時計は8時
The clock will soon strike 8,
夜空に待ってる星
the stars are waiting in the night sky.
なお これ 離れたところには
Furthermore, in this distant place,
もうないかもしれない
it may no longer be here.
月が きれいで 泣きそうになるのは
The reason the moon is so beautiful it makes me cry
いつの日にか 別れがくるから
is because one day, we'll have to say goodbye.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたい 流れる独り言
A passing monologue like a comet.
消えていく 残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The disappearing afterimages are a midnight prism.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
切な願い 誰かに届いたら
If this painful wish reached someone,
変われるかな 夜のフチを
I wonder if I can change,
なぞるような こんな僕でも
even someone like me who traces the edge of the night.
はるか彼方 僕らは
In the far distance,
出会ってしまった
we happened to meet.
カルマだから 何度も
It's karma, so we'll meet
出会ってしまうよ
again and again.
蜘蛛のすきまって
Between the gaps in the clouds.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜広げて 描こう絵空事
Spreading out the night and drawing a fantasy.
暗闇を 照らすような
Even if it's not a full moon
満月じゃなくても
that lights up the darkness.
だから集まって 星座になりたい
So I want to gather and become a constellation
色とりどりの 光放つような
one that emits colorful light.
つないだ線 解かないよ
I won't untie the lines we've connected
君がどんなに まぶしくても
No matter how dazzling you might be.
みなさーん！こんちゃわー！
Everyone! Hello!
はい、えーいつもの挨拶いきたいと思います。
Yes, uh, I'd like to do the usual greeting.
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！
The star's diamond in the rough that appeared like a comet!
アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
Idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei here!
すいちゃんはー？
Suichan is—?
今日もかわいい！
Cute today too!
今日もかわいい！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Cute today too! Thank you! Thank you!
皆さん、コメントしかと見届けさせていただいております。
Everyone, I'm making sure to see all your comments.
ありがとうございます！「今日も可愛い」ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you for the "You're cute today too"!
えー、本日、私誕生日なんです！
Uh, today is my birthday!
うわー！18歳になりました！
Whoa! I turned 18!
去年も18歳だった、一昨年も18歳だった。
I was 18 last year, and 18 the year before too.
そして、活動5周年になります！
And, it's my 5th anniversary of activities!
うわー、5周年。早かったような、
Whoa, 5 years. It felt fast,
短かったような... あれ、どっちも一緒だ。
it felt short... Wait, those are both the same.
はい、ということで。こちら星街すいせい5周年ライブで、
Yes, so. Please tweet a lot about this
たくさんツイートしてくださいね。よろしくお願いします。
Hoshimachi Suisei 5th Anniversary Live. Thank you.
このあともたくさん盛り上がる曲用意してるので、もっともっと盛り上がっていきましょう！
I have many more exciting songs ready after this, so let's get even more hyped!
それでは次の曲、行くぞーい！
Now then, for the next song, here we go!
マーシャル・マキシマイザー / 作詞・作曲・編曲 柊マグネタイト
Marshall Maximizer / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Hiiragi Magnetite
脳内展示室に 付き合わされる14ポンドの乱舞
A wild dance of 14 pounds forced upon the cerebral exhibition room
...もないけど 擬学的人の振りをしている
...though it's nothing, acting like a scholar,
君を待っている
I'm waiting for you.
ああ面倒だったから 君捨てた 余裕サイズ おさらば
Ah, because it was a bother, I threw you away.
Farewell to the oversized leisure.
申し訳ないけど すれ違うのに 無為に期待を 背負わせている
Sorry, but as we pass by,
I'm making you shoulder futile expectations.
夜更かしはイドの暴走
Staying up late is the ID running wild
目に焼き付いた青の感光
The blue exposure burned into my eyes
食べて すぐ寝て 牛になる
Eat, sleep right away, and become a cow
起きて また食べて 人でなし
Wake up, eat again, and you're no longer human
マーシャル・マキシマイザー 朽ちて相まって焦がした
Marshall Maximizer,
decaying and combining, I scorched it.
フェド・キョーコなんて言葉死んでしまう
Words like 'Fed Kyoko' end up dying.
だが つまみは回る感情から メイド
But the knob turns from the emotions, made.
作法 虚した 作法 虚せて疎い しまいにゃ 取り戻したい
Manners failed, manners faded and distant,
in the end, I want to take them back.
手もゲンジも 手落ちる 落ちる
Both hands and the Genji, falling out, falling down.
皿下見合わば つま先 帰り Faraway
Looking under the plate, on tip-toes, going home, Faraway.
昂然 擬態 君 繰り出すアラーム 吸収 温度 お笑い目途
Arrogant mimicry, you send out an alarm.
Absorption, temperature, a laughable target.
どうしようもないから 擬学的人の真似をしている 君へ
Because there's no other way,
to you, who's acting like a scholar.
簡単なら言葉信じていたいなら足りないよ
If it's easy, and you want to believe
the words, then it's not enough.
申し訳ないなら すでにアウトに不意に会話求まらないよ
If you're sorry, it's already out,
suddenly conversation won't be sought.
モラトリアム的人間
Moratorium-like human
最小公倍数断頭台
Least common multiple guillotine
食べて すぐ寝て 牛になる
Eat, sleep right away, and become a cow
起きて また食べて 人でなし
Wake up, eat again, and you're no longer human
触れてみたい秘密を壊してみたい 夜の中で
I want to touch the secrets,
I want to break them within the night.
間違いだらけの遊びをしようよ
Let's play a game full of mistakes.
シニカルナイトプラン
Cynical Night Plan
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Lyrics/Composition: Ayase
別に意味とかないけどさ 眠い目を擦る
It's not like it has any meaning,
I rub my sleepy eyes.
あれ待ち合わせは何時？ 君はまた履き違えてる
Wait, what time was the meeting?
You've got it wrong again.
また間違えてる それであなたは大人なの？
You made a mistake again.
And you call yourself an adult?
交わしていたいと言ったのは お互い様
It's both of us who said
we wanted to keep interacting.
目が合う度に名前を呼ばないで
Don't call my name every time our eyes meet.
触れていたいのか隠さないから
I won't hide if I want to keep touching,
私のフリした私で良ければどうぞ
so if the 'me' who's pretending to be me is okay,
then go ahead.
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色の様に
Like the scenery falling into my closing eyes,
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
the hazy me belongs to no one.
Baby, so feeling からかわないで
Baby, so feeling, don't tease me,
私だけに見せて歪な夜をどうぞ
show only me the distorted night, go ahead.
ああもう本当嫌嫌嫌
Ah, I really hate it, hate it, hate it.
どこかの誰かと 赤信号渡ればいいでしょ
Just go cross the red light with someone else.
ダメダメダメってわかるでしょ
You know it's no, no, no.
青に染まってたんじゃつまんない嫌
It's boring if it's just dyed blue, I hate it.
続々流れるテロップ 交わす言葉に絡めるシロップ
Successive scrolling tickers,
syrup intertwined with the words we exchange.
早くドキドキさせてよ ほら
Come on, make my heart race quickly.
舞い散る誰かと私のエゴ 止まんないわ
The ego of someone fluttering down and mine,
it won't stop.
いつものように 騙し騙しで重なる凶器
As always, the overlapping weapons of deception.
夢のように 自由に 後は手遅れ 落ちるだけ
Like a dream, freely, after that it's too late,
just falling.
触れてみたい秘密を壊してみたい 夜の中で
I want to touch the secrets,
I want to break them within the night.
間違いを繰り返して
Repeating mistakes over and over.
触れてみたい秘密を壊して知るよ 夜の街を
I'll know by touching the secrets and breaking them,
the streets at night.
モノローグ始めましてどうぞ
Monologue, nice to meet you, go ahead.
景色の様に
Like the scenery
霞む私は
I, who am hazy
誰のものでもないの Baby
belong to no one, Baby
そっぽ向かないで
Don't look away
私だけにみせて
Show only to me
歪な夜を
the distorted night
瞳に落ちる
Falling into my eyes
景色の様に
Like the scenery
霞む私は
I, who am hazy
誰のものでもないの Baby
belong to no one, Baby
そっぽ向かないで
Don't look away
私だけにみせて
Show only to me
歪な夜を
the distorted night
ほとほと...
completely...
それでは、次の曲行きますよ。
Now, let's go to the next song.
本日のゲスト、花譜ー！
Today's guest, KAF!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
歌：花譜×星街すいせい
作詞・作曲・編曲：ツミキ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
Vocals: KAF x Hoshimachi Suisei
Lyrics, Comp, Arr: Tsumiki
貴方にも忘れたい事
There must be things you want to forget
悲しい事
and sad things,
あるのかしらね
I wonder?
知らないだなんて
Shedding tears
涙を流すのは
while saying you don't know
ドラマチック語りきれない事よ
are things that can't be told dramatically
そんな事もつかない事
Things that aren't even like that,
くだらない事
silly things,
考えてばかりね
you're just thinking about them
雨が上がれば今そう
Now that the rain has stopped, yes,
欲深を想う
I think of greed
誰かの物になるんでしょう
You'll probably become someone else's property
嘘っぱちの
Even this phony
ランデブーも
rendezvous
今夜でおさらばよ
is farewell for tonight
七転八倒
Topsy-turvy,
前途多難で
a difficult future ahead
混ざれ 混ざれ ハッテンな
Mix it, mix it, Hatten-na
不安定なカケラ
Unstable fragments,
どこまで行くの
how far will you go?
貴方と一切合切 葬り去ってしまいたい
I want to bury everything and everyone with you
阿呆じゃないわ
I'm not a fool
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって
Even when that time comes,
どうにもならないぜ
it's no use
曖昧な
Ambiguous
感情論
emotional theories
揺らぎ取っ捕まえて
Just catching the fluctuations
滾るだけ
and boiling
私をかっさらって
Snatch me away
今、チェック・メイト
Now, checkmate
ああ ちゃんちゃらおかしい ハートばかり
Ah, it's so ridiculous, just hearts
掌がピクともしないわ
My palm doesn't even twitch
実体のない感情放っておいたって
Even if I leave these formless emotions alone
策略なんてありんすもに、何故
There are no strategies, so why?
ああ もう懲り懲りよ
Ah, I've had enough
私の計算のリズムもじっと堪えて
Enduring the rhythm of my calculations
取り繕って ああ ダーリン解体
Patching it up, ah, darling disassembly
年がら年中 リップ・サービス
Lip service all year round
トンカンかましてはヘキヘキ
Banging away, I'm disgusted
反転した フィール・ガール
Inverted Feel Girl
涙のメロディ
Melody of tears
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで
Now because of the music in my head
貴方の話は一向に聞き取れない
I can't hear a word you say
もしや真っ当なこと言っていい？
Perhaps I can say something decent?
回り出した ダンシング ダンシング
Starting to spin, dancing, dancing
忘れさせてよ
Let me forget
だけど一切合切 どうしてどうして
But everything, why, why?
なーなな はってんな
Na-na-na Hatten-na
不安定なカケラ
Unstable fragments,
消えないままで
remaining without disappearing
貴方と一切合切 食い違っても
Even if we disagree on everything with you
阿呆じゃないわ
I'm not a fool
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって
Even when that time comes,
どうにもならないぜ
it's no use
曖昧な
Ambiguous
感情論
emotional theories
揺らぎ取っ捕まえて
Just catching the fluctuations
滾るだけ
and boiling
私をかっさらって
Snatch me away
今、チェック・メイト
Now, checkmate
阿呆じゃないわ
I'm not a fool
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって
Even when that time comes,
どうにもならないぜ
it's no use
曖昧な
Ambiguous
感情論
emotional theories
揺らぎ取っ捕まえて
Just catching the fluctuations
滾るだけ
and boiling
私と確かめて
Confirm it with me
真っ平
Completely flat
阿呆じゃないわ
I'm not a fool
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって
Even when that time comes,
どうにもならないぜ
it's no use
曖昧な
Ambiguous
感情論
emotional theories
揺らぎ取っ捕まえて
Just catching the fluctuations
滾るだけ
and boiling
私をかっさらって
Snatch me away
今、チェック・メイト
Now, checkmate
わー！ありがとうございましたー！
Wow! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
花譜ちゃん、いつもの挨拶とかありますか？
KAF-chan, do you have your usual greeting?
あ、花譜です、こんばんは。
Ah, I'm KAF, good evening.
花譜ちゃんが来てくれましたー！
KAF-chan has come!
ありがとう、花譜ちゃん。
Thank you, KAF-chan.
えっと、すいちゃん...
Well, Sui-chan...
すいちゃん、そうなんですよ、呼んでくれるようになって。
Sui-chan, that's right, she started calling me that.
あの、一緒に歌うのは一年ぶりくらい？
Um, it's been about a year since we sang together?
そうだよね。
That's right.
最後のV-FESが最後で。
The last V-FES was the last time.
うんうん、V-FESが最後で。
Yeah, yeah. V-FES was the last.
あの、あれだったね、彩花。
Um, it was that, wasn't it? Saika.
彩花、歌いましたね。
Saika, we sang it.
今日は、花譜ちゃんの曲、トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴを歌わせていただきました。
Today, we sang KAF-chan's song, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
ありがとうございます、歌わせてくれて。
Thank you for letting us sing it.
いや、ありがとうございます。
No, thank you.
いや、こちらこそ本当に。
No, really, likewise.
あの、花譜ちゃんと言えば...
Um, speaking of KAF-chan...
このふわふわな...
This fluffy...
...ふわふわな喋り方と歌い方が特徴ですけれども、
...fluffy way of speaking and singing is her characteristic,
普段は何をされている方なんですか？
but what do you usually do?
普段は、歌を歌っています。
Usually, I'm singing songs.
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
皆さんも知ってると思うんですけど、トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ、これめちゃめちゃバズってますよね？
I'm sure you all know 'Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous' is really viral right now, right?
めちゃくちゃバズってて、すごいです。ねえ。
It's gone incredibly viral, it's amazing. Yeah.
あ、それはやっぱり認知されている、バズってるのは。
Oh, so it's widely recognized as being viral then.
はい。周りからも「すごいね」って。
Yes. People around me say, "That's amazing."
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ、今日歌う上で...
For singing 'Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous' today...
二人で振り付けも考えましたね。
...we thought of the choreography together.
そうですね。
That's right.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ...
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous...
ほぼでもね、可不ちゃんが考えてくれて。
But Kaf-chan thought of almost all of it.
いやいや、そんな...
No, no, not at all...
イエス！とか。
Like "Yes!"
めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
It's so cute.
可愛い、可不ちゃん！
So cute, Kaf-chan!
一緒にやってくれて、すぐ、「さすがや」って思って。
When we did it together, I immediately thought, "As expected!"
そんなことないです。可不ちゃん可愛いね。
Not at all. You're cute, Kaf-chan.
あ、あ、ああ〜。
Ah, ah, ahhh~
でもさ、お喋りするのはNHKラジオでちょっとね、お喋りしたぶりなので。
But well, it's been a while since we talked on NHK radio.
そうですね。
That's right.
お会いするのはでもお久しぶり感？
It feels like we haven't met in person for a while.
そうだ。
That's true.
その時にね、「すいちゃん」って呼んでくれるようになって。
Back then, she started calling me "Sui-chan."
すいちゃん！可不ちゃん！
Sui-chan! Kaf-chan!
はい、ありがとうございます。そのちょっとイチャイチャを皆さんにお届けしたんですが。
Yes, thank you. We've shown everyone a bit of flirting.
可不ちゃん、ちなみに何か宣伝することとかありますか？
By the way, Kaf-chan, is there anything you'd like to promote?
あ、実はですね、
Oh, actually,
サードアルバム「狂想」が3月8日から配信リリースされているので、ぜひそちらをチェックしていただきたいです。
my 3rd album 'Kyousou' has been released digitally since March 8th, so please check it out.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
見どころは何ですか？
What's the highlight?
全曲、聴いてほしい。
I want you to listen to all the songs.
全曲ぜひ聴いてください。
Please listen to all the songs.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
ということで、可不ちゃんでした！ありがとうございました！
So that was Kaf-chan! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
またね。
See you again.
みちづれ
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Michizure
Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
それでは、次のスペシャルゲスト、この方！
Now, for the next special guest, this person!
RAISE A SUILEN、RAYCHELL！
RAISE A SUILEN, RAYCHELL!
人の世はいついつまでも 間違い探しばかり
In this world of humans, forever and always, we do nothing but search for mistakes.
遊び飽きたら終わりよ
When you're tired of playing, it's over.
逃げるか蛇か勝てるかと 怯えて過ごすばかり
Should I run, is it a trap, can I win? Just spending time in fear.
醒め醒めと一人泣く
Waking up and crying alone.
あぁ こんな旅路を行くことが 人の情理とでも言うの？
Ah, is going on such a journey what they call human reason?
浮き身を窶せど上手くいかずに
No matter how much I devote myself, things don't go well.
今夜もまた嘆くんだけどきっと
Tonight I'll lament again, but surely...
これはパレードさ 足を引き摺ろうとも
This is a parade, even if we drag our feet.
この滲む痛みと引き換えに 有り余る喜びに巡り会えるの
In exchange for this spreading pain, we can encounter overflowing joy.
止まらないパレードさ
It's an unstoppable parade.
私が生きた証だから
Because it's the proof that I lived.
お気に召したなら共に行こう みちづれにしてあげるわ
If you like it, let's go together. I'll take you along with me.
うやむやで有耶無耶
Indistinct and vague.
知らない噂の一つや二つ
A rumor or two that I don't know.
目を瞑ってあげるわ
I'll close my eyes to them for you.
でも譲れない大事な思いは
But these precious feelings I can't give up,
歪むことなくちゃんと伝えたいの
I want to convey them properly without distortion.
私はここだよ ここで生きてるんだよ
I'm right here. I'm living right here.
あなたと同じ心臓で刻む
Beating with the same heart as yours,
鼓動に乗せて進むパレード
moving forward on the heartbeat, this parade.
どんな景色を見に行こう
What kind of scenery shall we go see?
こんな私のことを
Someone like me,
信じてくれるならどこまでも行けるもう
if you believe in me, I can go anywhere.
一人で泣いたりしないわ
I won't cry alone anymore.
そしていつの日か私と
And someday, when you and I,
あなたの旅が終わり迎えた日には
when our journey reaches its end,
抱え集めてきた荷物を全て
all the luggage we've gathered,
放り投げては笑い合おう
we'll toss it aside and laugh together.
そんな旅路を共に行こう
Let's go on such a journey together.
RAISE YOUR HELL or HELL!
HELL! or HELL?
作詞：織田あすか (Elements Garden)
作曲：上松範康 (Elements Garden)
編曲：菊田大介 (Elements Garden)
HELL! or HELL?
Lyrics: Asuka Oda (Elements Garden)
Composition: Noriyasu Agematsu (Elements Garden)
Arrangement: Daisuke Kikuta (Elements Garden)
HELL or HELL, WHICH DO YOU?
ボクのWinner 手繰り回した
My winner, I've reeled it in
覚悟はあるか？
Are you prepared?
RE-SAVE THE REALITY
肥大したこのPain
This swollen pain
弱いヤツほど口を回す
The weaker they are, the more they talk
HELL or HELL どちらが欲しい？
HELL or HELL, which do you want?
IT'S SUILEN BE DETERMINED
この言葉最後まで
Hear these words until the very end
焼き付けておけ
Burn them into your memory
今に 後悔せよ
You'll regret this soon
NOISELESS!!
YOU SHOUT OUT, THE MAXIMUM SOUND
死んでも曲げはしないから
Because even if I die, I won't bend
土になれば絶句
Speechless when returned to dust
この世の定めを知れよ
Know the laws of this world
仕方ない報いを今
Take your inevitable reward now
RAISE YOUR HELL or HELL!
自分だけが よければいいか
Is it enough if only you are well?
どの面下げて
How dare you?
YOU GOT THE MAXIMUM SOUND
誤魔化れば何でもOK
Anything's fine if you can fake it
さよなら常識は生きてるよね
Goodbye common sense, you're still alive, right?
HELL or HELL どちらも欲しい？
HELL or HELL, do you want both?
RAISE YOUR HELL or HELL!
上っ面の相手はしない
I won't deal with superficiality
劣化のブレスが
The breath of deterioration
ここで 終わりにする
Ends right here
NOISELESS!!
DON'T GIVE IN, その甘えは危険
Don't give in, that complacency is dangerous
怒りに呑まれるなよ
Don't be swallowed by anger
狂い咲いたアドレナリン
Adrenaline in full, mad bloom
舌先が動くワケじゃないさ
It's not like just the tip of my tongue is moving
答えちゃいな 今すぐほら
Give me your answer, right now, look
RAISE YOUR HELL or HELL!
静けさの中こそ
It is within the silence
真実がある
That truth exists
瞳 耳を澄ませ
Open your eyes, listen closely
NOISELESS!!
YOU SHOUT OUT, THE MAXIMUM SOUND
死んでも曲げはしないから
Because even if I die, I won't bend
土になれば絶句
Speechless when returned to dust
この世の定めを知れよ
Know the laws of this world
仕方ない報いを今
Take your inevitable reward now
RAISE YOUR HELL or HELL!
HELL or HELL, WHICH DO YOU?
ということで、RAISE A SUILENの皆さんに来ていただきましたー！
And so, we have the members of RAISE A SUILEN here with us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、嬉しすぎる。ありがとうございます。来てくださって。
Oh, I'm so happy. Thank you so much for coming.
自己紹介をお願いします。
Please introduce yourselves.
はい。RAISE A SUILEN ベースボーカル、レイヤです。
Yes. I'm LAYER, Bass & Vocal of RAISE A SUILEN.
ギターのロックです！
I'm LOCK on guitar!
ドラムのマスキングだ。
I'm MASKING on drums.
キーボードメイド、パレオです！
I'm PAREO, the Keyboard Maid!
プロデューサーそしてDJのチュチュよ！
I'm CHU2, the Producer and DJ!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
うわ、夢が叶った。ありがとうございます。
Wow, my dream came true. Thank you so much.
UNSTOPPABLE！
UNSTOPPABLE!
まず、１曲目にレイヤさんと『みちづれ』を歌わせていただいたんですが...
First of all, I got to sing 'Michizure' with LAYER-san as the first song...
もうレイヤさんの歌声にすごくぴったりで、
LAYER-san's voice fit the song so perfectly.
もうすごく嬉しかったです、私の曲を歌っていただけて。
I was so happy to have you sing my song.
いや、私もすごく嬉しかったです。
No, I was very happy too.
あ、本当ですか？ どうでしたか？
Oh, really? How was it?
いや、めちゃめちゃ難しい楽曲なんですけれども...
Well, it's a very difficult song, but...
めちゃめちゃかっこいいですよね。
It's really cool, isn't it?
そうなんです、すごいかっこよくて。あの、Ayaseさんに書き下ろしていただいた楽曲で...
Yes, it's very cool. It's a song written for me by Ayase-san.
今日レイヤさんと歌えるということで、すごい緊張していたんですけど、とっても完璧でした！
I was very nervous to sing it with LAYER-san today, but it was perfect!
いえいえ。私もすごく緊張したんですけれども、すごく楽しかったです。
No, no. I was also very nervous, but it was a lot of fun.
ありがとうございます！ 嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
そしてすいせいには私たちの
And Suisei sang our
『HELL! or HELL?』を歌ってもらったけど、感想聞かせてくださいますか？
'Hell! or Hell?', but can you tell us how you felt?
あの、この曲もすごい難しかったですし、あと、なんか、すごい激しかったですよね！
Well, this song was also very difficult, and it was really intense!
もう、あと皆さんのパフォーマンスもすごかったので、
And everyone's performance was amazing,
もう感動しました。生でこんな風に見られて、ありがとうございます。
so I was moved. Thank you for letting me see it like this.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
もうすごい光栄でした。
It was a great honor.
あと私、皆さんのライブにも実は行かせていただいたことがありまして...
And actually, I've been to your live shows before.
もうその時も『HELL! or HELL?』すごい盛り上がらせていただきました。
Even then, 'Hell! or Hell?' was so exciting.
嬉しいわ！ ありがとうございます！
I'm happy! Thank you!
サビでこうやりました！
I did this during the chorus!
激しいわね。
It was intense, wasn't it?
激しかった！
It was intense!
すいせいさんは『HELL! or HELL?』でヘドバンをしていましたよね！
Suisei-san, you were headbanging during 'Hell! or Hell?', weren't you?
はい！ そうなんです！ させていただきました！
Yes! I did it!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
あ、なんか、すごい脳震盪が起こりそうな...
Well, I felt like I was going to get a concussion...
これ、いつも皆さんだって弾きながらやられてるのがすごいなと思って。
I thought it was amazing that you guys always do that while playing.
もう慣れっこなんですか、それは。
Are you used to it?
そうですね。
Well...
ライフワークです！
It's my life's work!
ライフワークなんですか？！
Life's work?!
へぇ、すごい！
Wow, that's amazing!
あれ、マスキングさんさっきからずいぶんと静かですが...
Wait, MASKING-san has been very quiet for a while...
もしかして、すいちゃんの可愛さに照れちゃってます？
Could it be that you're shy because of Sui-chan's cuteness?
まさか。
No way.
でも、いいヘドバンだったぜ。
But it was a good headbang.
エヘヘ！ ありがとうございます！
Hehe! Thank you!
うわ、マスキングさん！ う、嬉しいです！
Wow, MASKING-san! I'm so happy!
え、ちょっとね、じゃあ時間もありますので、
Well, we have some time,
ちょっと皆さんとツーショット、いいですか？
so can I take some two-shots with everyone?
カメラさーん！
Camera-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
やった、嬉しい！ かわいい、かわいい！
Yay, I'm happy! Cute, cute!
あ、ハート！
Oh, a heart!
あ、かわいい！ 嬉しい！
Oh, cute! I'm happy!
楽しんでるわね。
You're enjoying yourselves, aren't you?
あ、ロックだ！ すいせいさーん！
Oh, it's LOCK! Suisei-san!
かわいい、かわいいです！
Cute, you're cute!
おい、ロック、デレデレしすぎよ。
Hey, LOCK, you're grinning too much.
もうこんな可愛い方にギターすごいですねって
To have such a cute person say
言われるのがめっちゃすごい...
my guitar is amazing is just...
とんでもないです、ありがとうございます！
Not at all, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
よしよし、よしよし。
There, there.
チュチュさーん！
CHU2-san!
すいせい本物よ！ 本物よ！ 本物よ！ いつもお歌聴いてるわ。
Suisei, the real deal! The real deal! The real deal! I always listen to your songs.
え、本当に？！
Wait, really?!
オリジナル曲も、カバー曲も！ 『THE FIRST TAKE』も大好きよ。
Both your original songs and covers! I love 'THE FIRST TAKE' too.
チュチュさん、いいんですか？ そんなにお褒めいただいちゃって。
CHU2-san, is it okay? I got so many compliments.
UNSTOPPABLE！
UNSTOPPABLE!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
チュチュさんがこんなにお褒めになって。
CHU2-san praised me so much.
嬉しいわね、パレオ。
I'm so happy, PAREO.
羨ましい！
I'm so jealous!
マスキングさん！
MASKING-san!
お、おい、お前、可愛いな...
H-hey, you... are cute.
やめてくださいよ！ マスキングさんの方が可愛いです！
Stop it! MASKING-san is cuter!
本当か？ ありがとうな。
Really? Thanks.
かわいい！
So cute!
マスキング顔赤い！
MASKING's face is red!
初見ね！
It's rare to see that!
レイヤさん、じゃあ。
LAYER-san, then.
うわ！ RASポーズ！ うわ、嬉しい！
Wow! RAS pose! Wow, I'm happy!
すいちゃん、ありがとう。
Sui-chan, thank you.
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much!
うわ、もうこんな夢が叶い... 私、今日誕生日なんですよ、実は。
Wow, a dream came true. Actually, today is my birthday!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！ もう最高のプレゼントになりました。本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you! It was the best present. Thank you so much!
次はね、私もあの皆さんのところにお邪魔したいななんて、ヘヘッ。
Next time, I'd like to visit you guys too. Hehe.
バンドリさん、よろしくお願いします！
BanG Dream!, please!
ということで、以上スペシャルゲスト、
So, that was our special guest,
RAISE A SUILENの皆さんでした！ ありがとうございました！
RAISE A SUILEN! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
祈る 空に 声が 流星が
Praying to the sky, voices like shooting stars...
ハピネスと ミラクルを
...happiness and miracles...
始まりを 告げている
...are signaling the beginning.
バンドリ！ ガールズバンドパーティ！
BanG Dream! Girls Band Party!
「3Dライブモード」がついに登場！
3D Live Mode finally arrives!
ハイ! ハイ! ハイ! ハッ!
Hi! Hi! Hi! Ha!
バンドリ! ガールズバンドパーティ!
Bang Dream! Girls Band Party!
Yeah! Uh-huh
Humdee-hum
Heart to heart
Let's go!
Yeah!
Happy day, happy day, KU-RU-RU-RU happy day
Ooh-wow!
空は繋がっているよ
The sky is connected
海も繋がっているよ (君と)
The sea is connected too (with you)
いつだって いつだって
Anytime, anytime
心の中で 会えるから
Because we can meet in our hearts
瞳を閉じれば Over the moon
If I close my eyes, Over the moon
僕らのステージ Endless with me
Our stage, Endless with me
飛び込んだ世界で
In the world I jumped into
夢よ回れ Forever & ever
Let dreams spin, Forever & ever
どうなっちゃうんだ 楽しなら
I wonder what will happen, if it's fun
大丈夫さ
It'll be alright
新しいやり方で Make you happy
In a new way, Make you happy
おんなじ気持ちだって 分かっちゃう
I can tell we feel the same
いつも分かっちゃう
I can always tell
君の思いが 分かっちゃうんだ
I can tell how you feel
Yeah!
空へ向かって歌う
Singing towards the sky
海に語りかけてる (君に)
Talking to the sea (to you)
いつだって いつだって
Anytime, anytime
耳を澄ませば 聞こえるよ
If I listen closely, I can hear you
Hey!
瞳を開いても 終わらない
Even if I open my eyes, it doesn't end
僕らのステージは Endless passion
Our stage is Endless passion
重なった世界で
In our overlapping worlds
夢よ回れ Forever & ever
Let dreams spin, Forever & ever
どうなっちゃいたい
I wonder what I want to become
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to play forever and ever
遠くでも君の声で Make me happy
Even from afar, your voice makes me happy
おんなじ気持ちだよね
We feel the same, don't we?
君の願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can tell what your wish is
繋がりたい いつだって
I want to connect, always
君へと繋がる場所がある
There is a place that connects to you
Yeah! Uh-huh
信じているんだ 君には伝わると
I believe that it will reach you
大好きが伝わると
That my love will reach you
大好き!
I love you!
Hey!
これだけは変わらない
Only this will never change
To make you happy
出会えたことがラッキー
Being able to meet you is lucky
君が笑えばハッピー
If you smile, I'm happy
Yeah!
アテンションだね 君が
I'm paying attention to you
大好きだよ
I love you
どうなっちゃいたい
I wonder what I want to become
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to play forever and ever
遠くでも君の声で Make me happy
Even from afar, your voice makes me happy
おんなじ気持ちだよね
We feel the same, don't we?
君の願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can tell what your wish is
どうなっても楽しいなら
No matter what, if it's fun
大丈夫さ
It'll be alright
新しいやり方で Make you happy
In a new way, Make you happy
おんなじ気持ちだって 分かっちゃう
I can tell we feel the same
いつも分かっちゃう
I can always tell
君の思いが 分かっちゃうんだ
I can tell how you feel
Yeah!
Happy day, happy day, KU-RU-RU-RU happy day
Ooh-wow!
Happy day, happy day
揺らせ 1秒懸けたら サマーゲイツ
Shake it, if I spend one second, Summer Gates
夢の道はストレート
The road of dreams is straight
視線誰にも譲れない
I won't give my gaze to anyone
Please, gaze on me きっと始まる
Please, gaze on me, it'll surely start
Fantastic time
Gaze on Me!
Go as spotlight
I am the heroine
見つめていて
Keep looking at me
耳元頂戴 Free gaze on me
Whisper in my ear, free gaze on me
きっと始まる Fantastic time
Surely a fantastic time is about to start
みんな準備はいいですか？
Is everyone ready?
Burning
頷いて陽炎も Heat up
Nod, and even the heat haze will heat up
どうしよう上昇上がる空気
What to do with this rising atmosphere
Next go
彷徨う燃えて最高
Wandering, burning, it's the best
Me
負けられない 幸福をハートも
I won't lose, not this happiness or my heart
駆け引きは No no game
The bargaining is a no-no game
開いたなら 一瞬のままで
Once it opens, stay as you are in this moment
走れ虹のほうへ
Run towards the rainbow
揺らせ一秒懸けたら様々
Shake it, once a second is spent, everything changes
夢の道はずっとレッド
The dream road is always red
視線誰にも譲れない
I won't let anyone else have your gaze
Free gaze on me
きっと沸き出す Fantastic time
Surely a fantastic time will overflow
Go as spotlight
I am the heroine
見つめていて
Keep looking at me
耳元頂戴 Free gaze on me
Whisper in my ear, free gaze on me
きっと沸き出す Fantastic time
Surely a fantastic time will overflow
絶対最上掴みたい Feeling
Feeling like I definitely want to grasp the top
全身全霊めぐるから Get hot
It circulates through my whole being, so get hot
テンション高揚星まで今
High tension, reaching for the stars now
ライトアップのっで一緒かい？
Riding the light up, are we together?
Peak
迎える時 遠慮はいらない
When the time comes, there's no need to hold back
せめぎ合いを Oh oh bad
This struggle is oh-oh-bad
汗とプライド 知恵の運命
Sweat and pride, the fate of wisdom
連れ出すのほうへ
Taking you out to that place
挑む世界は魅惑のサンライトフロア
The world I challenge is a charming sunlight floor
天井知らずのボルテージ
Boundless voltage
火照る季節をものにして
Making this burning season my own
Free gaze on me
クラリさせたい Exciting time
I want to make you dizzy, exciting time
Go as spotlight
I am the heroine
見つめていて
Keep looking at me
耳元頂戴 Free gaze on me
Whisper in my ear, free gaze on me
クラリさせたい Exciting time
I want to make you dizzy, exciting time
止まらない私の真夏 駆け出せたら Venus
My midsummer won't stop, if I start running, I'm Venus
熱くなれば一歩でチェンジ・アンド・ハッピー
If it gets hot, one step to change and happy
眩しすぎる今日 踊るように手にしよう
Let's grab today as if dancing, it's too bright
ビートは止まらない
The beat won't stop
Keep
思うままに身を預けて
Surrender yourself as you please
灼熱へ Go go hot
Into the scorching heat, go-go-hot
己のリズム打ち鳴らして
Let your own rhythm ring out
走れ虹のほうへ
Run towards the rainbow
揺らせ一秒懸けたら様々
Shake it, once a second is spent, everything changes
夢の道はずっとレッド
The dream road is always red
視線誰にも譲れない
I won't let anyone else have your gaze
Free gaze on me
きっと始まる Fantastic time
Surely a fantastic time is about to start
Go as spotlight
I am the heroine
見つめていて
Keep looking at me
耳元頂戴 Free gaze on me
Whisper in my ear, free gaze on me
きっと始まる Fantastic time
Surely a fantastic time is about to start
止んだクラクション さっきまでのヒステリックな街角
The horn stopped, the hysterical street corner until just now
喧騒を脱いで 煌めき取り戻す
Shedding the hustle and bustle, reclaiming the sparkle
Hey join us be a starry jet
夜空を駆けるストリーム
A stream running through the night sky
Join us be a starry jet
乗り遅れないでね
Don't be late
満天中心地 選りすぐりの音楽達を
From the feeling of the whole sky, select music
散りばめチェリー 輝きで満たすよ
Sprinkling cherries, I'll fill it with radiance
最高今宵彗星になろうよ
It's the best, tonight let's become comets
始まり眠れる街
Starting, the sleeping city
君と彗星になろうだ
Let's become a comet together
盛り上がろう
Let's get excited
Take you higher 手を取って
Take you higher, take my hand
パーティは始まったばかり
The party has only just begun
Take you higher 目覚めてよ
Take you higher, wake up
さあ 一緒に Fly!
Now, let's fly together!
そっと閉じて 瞼の奥
Gently close them, deep behind your eyelids
光を追いかける
Chasing the light
消えてしまう前に
Before it fades away
覚えておきたくて
I want to remember it
ねぇ 朝が来るなんて
Hey, how inconvenient
どれだけ不便なんだなんて
for the morning to come
自問自答ループ くらいすれば上機嫌
Just looping my internal monologue
keeps me in a good mood
Oh, it's please, please どなた様も Attention please
Oh, it's please, please,
everyone, attention please
明日へとっておきの想いは
I'll save my special feelings for tomorrow
Midnight Bay 決めたんだね
You've decided at Midnight Bay
君の生き方が綺麗なんだ
Your way of life is beautiful
それぞれが Trendy 輝きで満ちる
Each one is trendy, filled with radiance
ここからは私のモノマネを皆さんにしてもらいます。
From here, I want you all to mimic me.
目の前でやってください！
Please do it right in front of me!
私がやったクラップのリズムを真似してくださいね！
Please mimic the rhythm of the claps I do!
それじゃあ、いきますよ！
Well then, here we go!
パン パパ パン はい！
Clap clap-clap clap, go!
パパン パパン はい！
Clap-clap clap-clap, go!
パパン パパン パンパンパン はい！
Clap-clap clap-clap clap-clap-clap, go!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
こういう彗星になろうよ
Let's become a comet like this
君と彗星になろうだ
Let's become a comet together
煌めく星に
In the twinkling stars
踊る星のひとつぶさえ
If even a single dancing star
この街に欠かせないのなら
Is indispensable to this city
そんな今日が本物
Then today is the real thing
今 言えるかも
Maybe I can say it now
どこまでも Starry Jet
To the ends of the earth, Starry Jet
このまま夜が明けるまで
Just like this, until the night ends
特別な Starry Jet
A special Starry Jet
まだ 終わらない
It's not over yet
盛り上がれ Starry Jet
Get excited, Starry Jet
朝が来たって忘れない
I won't forget, even when morning comes
最高の Starry Jet
The best Starry Jet
さあ 一緒に Fly!
Now, let's fly together!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ふぅー！
Phew!
ダンサーさんもありがとうございます！
Thanks to the dancers as well!
はぁ、ありがとうございます。
Haah, thank you.
ちょっとゼェハァしているんですけれども。
I'm a bit out of breath, but...
えー、ここからは告知タイムになります！
Well, from here on, it's announcement time!
うわー！
Wah!
本日告知がたくさんありますが、駆け足でやっていきたいと思います。
There are many announcements today,
so I'll go through them quickly.
もう9時ですので。まずは、こちら！
It's already 9 o'clock. First, this!
本日共演したRAISE A SUILENさんが登場しているバンドリ！ガールズバンドパーティ！は、
BanG Dream! Girls Band Party!, featuring RAISE A SUILEN
who performed with me today,
3月16日に6周年を迎え、超大型アップデートを実施しました。
celebrated its 6th anniversary on March 16th
with a massive update.
超大型アップデートにより、3Dライブモードが実装され、
With the massive update,
3D Live Mode has been implemented,
自分の好きなバンド編成で、好きな衣装を着せて、
and you can enjoy the rhythm game
with your favorite band members
リズムゲームが楽しめるそうです！
wearing your favorite outfits!
ぜひ、遊んでみてください！
Please give it a try!
えー、お次、お次、はぁ、はぁ。
Um, next, next... *pant pant*
レギュラー化が発表されていたNHKラジオ『ぶいあーる！』ですが、
For the NHK Radio "V-R!",
which was announced to become a regular show,
この度、公式Twitterができました！
an official Twitter account has been created!
私もこのあとリツイートするので、皆さんもフォローしておいてください。
I'll retweet it after this, so please follow them.
初回放送は4月9日日曜日22時40分からです。
The first broadcast will be on
Sunday, April 9th, from 22:40.
ふぅ。
Phew.
次は新情報ですよ！
Next is new information!
えー、いきます！どん！
Um, here it is! Bam!
なんと、この度ハウス食品さん、イトーヨーカドーさんとコラボさせていただきました！
Believe it or not, I've collaborated with
House Foods and Ito-Yokado!
オリジナルレトルトカレー『#星街家のカレー』の発売が決定しました！
The release of an original retort curry,
"Hoshimachi Family Curry," has been decided!
わー！
Wow!
何パターンもね試食を作っていただきまして、私もしっかり監修を重ねて、
We had them make many test patterns for tasting,
and I carefully supervised them.
名前の通りすいちゃんの実家の味にできる限り近づけた味わいとなっております。
As the name suggests, the flavor is as close
as possible to Sui-chan's family home.
もちろん、具の野菜は、じゃがいもと玉ねぎだけになってますよ。
Of course, the only vegetables in it
are potatoes and onions.
こちらは、4月10日からイトーヨーカドーネット通販で予約が開始予定となります。
Pre-orders will start on the
Ito-Yokado online shop from April 10th.
何やらカレーにもおまけもついてくるそうなんですが、
It seems there's also a bonus
included with the curry,
このボカされているパッケージも含めて詳細は後日改めて発表となります。
but details, including the blurred package,
will be announced later.
お楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
ふぅー、わー。
Phew, wow.
そして、お次。
And next.
えー、この度専門学校HALさんの2023年度CMソングの歌唱を担当することに...
Um, I'll be in charge of singing the 2023 CM song
for Vocational School HAL...
…ことになりました！
…it has been decided!
曲を誰が作ったかは明日発表されるみたいです。
The composer of the song will apparently be announced tomorrow.
CMは24日金曜日からHALのホームページで見れますので、ぜひチェックしてください。
The CM will be available on HAL's website from Friday the 24th, so please check it out.
そして、このCMはなんとテレビでも流れるんです。
And, this CM will actually be shown on TV as well.
見た人はぜひツイートで教えてください！
If you see it, please let me know via tweet!
ふぅ、一息ついて。
Whew, catching my breath.
では、次のVTR行きますよ、ドン！
Now, here's the next VTR. Boom!
MIDNIGHT GRAND ORCHESTRA 1st LIVE
OVERTURE 2023.06.14 Blu-ray & DVD Release
Midnight Grand Orchestra
2nd MINI ALBUM 制作決定！
2nd MINI ALBUM production confirmed!
Hello everybody. Thanks for joining the Real World Arcade party.
Are you ready? Yes, it's you over there with the heavy burden on your shoulders.
Give these star lights back to you. Why don't you come out with me? Let's go!
みちづれ
配信終了後 MVプレミア公開
Michizure
MV premiere after the stream
いつも通りはいついつまでも…
As usual, forever and ever…
星が揺らいで　秘密を見ている
Stars are wavering, watching our secrets
焦がれたその音が　待ってるの
The sound I longed for is waiting
煌めく心　秘めてる日々に
To the days holding my sparkling heart hidden
届けるこのメロディ
I deliver this melody
窓から覗いた　雨降る街並みを
Looking through the window at the rainy cityscape
弾ける音だから　ポケットに詰め込んで
Since they're popping sounds, I'll stuff them in my pocket
ラッタッタ　君の好きな　ちょっと
Rat-tat-tat, to a slightly
いなせなステップに乗せて
Stylish step that you like
魔法のような　ナイトが
A night like magic
私を照らしてる
Is shining on me
星を繋いで　夢を描くよ
Connecting the stars, I'll draw a dream
焦がれたその声が　呼んでるの
The voice I longed for is calling
煌めく心　もっともっと君に
My sparkling heart, even more to you
届けるこのメロディ
I deliver this melody
このままじゃね　終われない
It can't end like this
特別なステージ　踊り明かすの
Dancing through the night on a special stage
このままじっとしてられない
I can't just stay still like this
走り出そうよ　明日は晴れるから
Let's start running, for tomorrow will be sunny
夜が醒めない　カーテンを開いても
The night doesn't awaken even if I open the curtains
憂鬱空想だって　ゴミ箱へ流した
I've even flushed melancholy fantasies into the trash
レッツゴー　いつも着てた　ちょっと
Let's go, changing into my slightly
勝負服に着替えて
Stylish go-to clothes
魔法のような　ドレスが
A dress like magic
ふわりと翻る
Flutters softly
満天の星空にほら　浮かべてみて
Look, try floating in the starry sky
明日の星を
Tomorrow's star
...ジョン
...vision
そこで見える
Visible from there
そこで見えるなら
If you can see it from there
もっと飛べるよ
Then I can fly even higher
満開の笑顔なら
With your smile in full bloom
ほら
Come on
歌ってみて このときめき
Sing out this excitement
そこで会える
I can meet you there
そこで会えるから
Because I can meet you there
だってきっと
Because surely
世界は変わるから
The world will change
明日晴れるから
Because it'll be sunny tomorrow
星を紡いで
Spinning the stars together
夢を描くよ
I'll paint my dreams
焦がれたその声が
That voice I yearned for
呼んでるの
Is calling out to me
煌めく空
In the sparkling sky
もっと遠く君に
To you, even further away
届ける
I'll deliver
このメロディ
This melody
このままじゃね
I can't let it
終われない
End like this
スペシャルのステージ
On this special stage
踊り明かすの
I'll dance the night away
このままじっとしてられない
I can't just stand still like this
走り出すよ
I'm going to start running
世界は変わるから
Because the world will change
明日晴れるから
Because it'll be sunny tomorrow
明日会えるから
Because I'll see you tomorrow
ありがとう！
Thank you!
星街すいせい誕生日＆活動5周年記念グッズ、今年も販売します！
Hoshimachi Suisei Birthday & 5th Anniversary Goods will be on sale again this year!
この後すぐ販売開始です。
Sales will start right after this.
気になるグッズ内容は…
The contents of the goods are...
ひなつ先生描き下ろしのキャンバスアート。
Canvas art illustrated by Hinatsu-sensei.
れいるか先生描き下ろしのランダムラバーキーホルダー。
Random rubber keychains illustrated by Reiruka-sensei.
結構大きいぞ、すいちゃんクッション。
It's quite big, the Suichan cushion.
普段使いもできる、COMETクリアショルダーバッグ。
The COMET clear shoulder bag, which can be used daily.
フルセット販売もあります。
Full set sales are also available.
フルセットを購入してくださった方には、箔押し複製サイン＆複製メッセージ入りのポストカードがついてきます。
Those who purchase the full set will receive a postcard with a foil-stamped replica signature and message.
メッセージは届いてからのお楽しみです。
The message is for you to look forward to until it arrives.
ぜひ買ってください！
Please do buy them!
4/1 ??????